VILANE GONÇALVES SALES

POST DOCTORAL RESEARCH SCIENTIST ♥ KÖNIZ, 3098, SWITZERLAND +410763915388

• DETAILS •

Muhlernstrasse, 204 Köniz, 3098 Switzerland +410763915388 vilane.g.sales@gmail.com

> Nationality Brazilian

LINKS

Linkedin

Google Scholar

° SKILLS °

Matlab

R

Python

ArcGIS

Big Data

Git

JavaScript

MySQL

Machine Learning

LANGUAGES

Portuguese

English

German

Spanish; Castilian

CHARACTERISTICS

Fast Learner, Leadership, Team Work, Integrity, Working under Pressure, Communication Skills, Organization Skills, Analytical Behaviour, Multi-tasking, Work/Life Balance

PROFILE

Vilane Gonçalves Sales works as a postdoctoral researcher for the World Trade Institute (WTI) and the Oeschger Centre for Climate Change Research (OCCR) at the University of Bern (CH). She holds a PhD in Economics from the University of Birmingham (UK) (2015–2019). She received a Full Doctoral Scholarship/CAPES (Brazil). She has expertise in environmental econometrics, extreme statistics, climate change economics, data analysis, big data, and geographic information systems (GIS). She is also interested in the interconnection of climate change, economics, and artificial intelligence (AI), such as data mining and natural language processing.

★ RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Natural disasters and climate change
- Sustainable development, climate and biodiversity conservation
- Climate Change and AI
- Deforestation and environmental policies

EDUCATION

PhD in Economics, University of Birmingham, Birmingham (UK)

2015 - 2019

Essays on the Economics and Policies of Deforestation in Brazil

MPhil in Management and Rural Development, Universidade Federal Rural de Pernambuco, Recife (BR)

2013 - 2015

Distinction

BA Economics, Universidade Federal Rural de Pernambuco, Recife (BR)

2008 - 2012

Academic Honors Diploma (First Class)

★ RELEVANT INFORMATION

Articles Published

Sales, Vilane G., Eric Strobl, and Robert JR Elliott. "Cloud cover and its impact on Brazil's deforestation satellite monitoring program: Evidence from the cerrado biome of the Brazilian Legal Amazon." *Applied Geography* 140 (2022): 102651. Keywords: Remote sensing; Survival analysis; Environmental policies; Forest disturbance

Articles Accepted

Sales, Vilane G., Eric Strobl. Using extreme value theory to assess the mortality risk of tornado outbreaks (Submitted to International Journal of Disaster Risk Science - *Accepted*)

Fornalé, Elisa, Cristani, Federica, **Sales, Vilane G.** Sustainable Management of Fisheries Resources: Legal Challenges Faced in the Mediterranean Region (Submitted to the Italian Yearbook of International Law - *Accepted*)

Submitted Articles

Sales, Vilane G. Modelling non-linear deforestation trends for an Ecological Tension Zone in Brazil. (Submitted to Science of Remote Sensing)

Moret, Elise, **Sales, Vilane G.**, Strobl, Eric. Extreme Value Analysis of Avalanche Damaged Buildings in the Swiss Alps (Submitted to Environmental Hazards)

Working Papers, Bern

2019 — Present

Sales, Vilane G., Eric Strobl, and Robert JR Elliott. Political Deforestation in the Brazilian Amazon.

Keller, Michael, Eric Strobl, **Sales, Vilane G**. Large Wildfires in Southern Switzerland: An Extreme Value Analysis

Blanc, Elodie, Jacob, Arthur L., Eric Strobl, **Sales, Vilane G**. Biodiversity and Crops in New Zealand

Sales, Vilane G., Eric Strobl. The Economic Impact of Extreme Precipitation: A Brazilian Study Case

Sales, Vilane G. Web Scraping and Text Mining of Brazilian News Articles About Environment: Sentiment Analysis

Scholarships, certifications, honours and awards

2008 - 2019

Coordination for the Improvement of Higher Education Personnel (CAPES) "PhD Abroad – Doutorado Pleno no Exterior" - 2015-2019

Coordination for the Improvement of Higher Education Personnel (CAPES) "First Place Master Position Scholarship" - 2013-2015

Coordination for the Improvement of Higher Education Personnel (CAPES) "Scientific Initiation Program" - 2008 - 2012

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Post Doctoral Research at University of Bern, Bern

2019 — Present

Teaching

- Deliver teaching for the undergraduate and postgraduate course(s) as appropriate.
- Develop and maintain involvement in teaching plans concerning teaching developments ongoing throughout the year.
- Practical organizational skills to manage time and priorities teaching and administrative duties.

Research

Functioning somewhat independently, design, organize, and conduct highly
specialized and advanced statistical analysis and, in some cases, develop new
protocols; summarize findings and publish results in research journals; assume
general responsibility for the scientific operations of the laboratory; provide
supervision and guidance to master students, bachelor students, and other
researchers.

Lecturer (MSc): Environmental Econometrics at University of Bern, Bern 2021 – 2022

- Take part in the assessment process by utilizing a range of methods and approaches and offering students effective, timely, and suitable feedback to aid in their learning.
- Help in the supervision of practical work by providing advice on skills, methods, and procedures that will aid in information transfer.
- Contribute to the curriculum's continuing development and design in a way that promotes a research-based and scholarly approach to student learning.
- Pursue professional development opportunities as necessary and to maintain an up-to-date knowledge base on assigned subjects.

- Perform restricted administrative responsibilities as assigned by the subject's or school's head of school.
- Pursue professional development to stay current and guarantee that new developments in knowledge are applied to teaching.

Lecturer (MSc): Environmental Economics for Non-Economists at University of Bern, Bern

2019 - 2020

- Take part in the assessment process by utilizing a range of methods and approaches and offering students effective, timely, and suitable feedback to aid in their learning.
- Help in the supervision of practical work by providing advice on skills, methods, and procedures that will aid in information transfer.
- Contribute to the curriculum's continuing development and design in a way that promotes a research-based and scholarly approach to student learning.
- Pursue professional development opportunities as necessary and to maintain an up-to-date knowledge base on assigned subjects.
- Perform restricted administrative responsibilities as assigned by the subject's or school's head of school.
- Pursue professional development to stay current and guarantee that new developments in knowledge are applied to teaching.

Teaching Assistant (MSc): Political Economy and Economic Policy at University of Birmingham , Birmingham (UK)

2019 - 2019

 Conduct various instructional and assessment activities, which may include tutorials, seminars, and lectures in some cases. Contribute to developing appropriate instructional materials by ensuring that content and delivery methods align with learning objectives.

Teaching Assistant (Undergraduate): Environmental Economics at University of Birmingham at University of Birmingham, Birmingham (UK)

2018 - 2018

 Participate in the assessment process, use various methods and techniques and provide practical, timely and appropriate feedback to students to support their learning.

Teaching Assistant (Undergraduate): Sustainable Development: Economy and Environment at University of Birmingham , Birmingham (UK)

2017 - 2018

 Carry out a variety of responsibilities related to teaching enrolled students and associated administration effectively and efficiently as desired by the Head of Subject and contribute to the attainment of the Economics Department strategic objectives.

■ REFERENCES

Eric Strobl from University of Bern

eastrobl13@gmail.com

Robert Elliott from University of Birmingham

R.J.Elliott@bham.ac.uk

COURSES

Introduction to Python, University of Birmingham

2018 - 2018

The Unix Shell, Version Control with Git, and Programming with Python, Software Carpentry / University of Birmingham

2018 - 2018

ArcGis I, II, III , Imagem – Esri Official Distributor

2015 - 2017

★ NEWS

BIFoR wider forested landscapes related research, Birmingham, UK

https://www.birmingham.ac.uk/research/bifor/bifor-wider-research/wider-research.aspx